Guide to the Bernard Rosenblatt Regional Theatre Council for Northern California and Nevada papers, 1938-1979
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Bernard Rosenblatt Regional Theatre Council for Northern California and Nevada papers
1938-1979
C0160
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
1.5 linear feet, (3 boxes)
This collection documents Bernard Rosenblatt's involvement in the Regional Theater Council for Northern California and Nevada, as well as related organizations. It also includes a collection of playbills from around the United States dating from 1938-1979.
Rosenblatt, Bernard
Acquisition Information
Donated by Bernard Rosenblatt in 1995.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds the which include extensive documentation of ANTA, as well as the which was an ANTA production.
Historical Information
The Regional Theater Council (RTC) for Northern California and Nevada was a regional affiliate of the American National Theatre and Academy (ANTA), an organization created to promote and support the development of American theatre. RTC, founded in the early 1950s, drew its membership from community and university theatres around the region. RTC seems to have disbanded by 1969 due to lack of interest and fragmentation and absorption by other related organizations, such as the California Educational Theater Association (CETA), the Northern California District of the American Educational Theater Association (NCD-AETA), and the American Community Theater Association (ACTA). Bernard Rosenblatt, a professor at San Joaquin Delta College, served as president of RTC in the mid and late 1960s, and served as Vice President of the NCD-AETA upon its formation in 1968.
Scope and Content
The collection documents the activities of Bernard Rosenblatt and the Regional Theater Council for Northern California and Nevada, as well as related organizations such as the Northern California District of the American Educational Theatre Association and the American Community Theatre Association. Types of records include correspondence, meeting minutes, organizational constitutions, histories, and newsletters dating from 1960-1969. Also included is Bernard Rosenblatt's collection of theatre programs from institutions across the United States (from the Metropolitan Opera to community theatre productions) dating from 1938-1979. The organizational records are located in boxes 1 and 2, and the theatre programs are located in boxes 2 and 3.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three boxes by format.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
American National Theatre and Academy.
Subjects:
Theater programs.; Theater--United States.
Contents List
- RTC Board Minutes, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- RTC Board Minutes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- RTC Board Minutes, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- RTC Board Minutes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- RTC Board Minutes, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- RTC Board Minutes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- RTC Board Minutes, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Regional Theatre Council correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Regional Theatre Council correspondence, Future Board Meetings, and Governing documents, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 7th Annual A.N.T.A. National Assembly Commemorative Souvenir Journal, June 23-26, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- RTC Callboard Newsletter, Regional Theatre Council, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- RTC Letterhead, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Regional Theatre Council Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- RTC: General Meetings, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- RTC Constitution (NCD) Proposed, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- RTC Constitution, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Regional Theatre Council Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Northern California District, American Theater Association Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "The Regional Theatre Council of Northern California and Nevada" by Leroy King, early 1960s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Regional Theatre Council Newsletter information, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- American National Theatre Academy information, articles, mid 1960s (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Northern California District Conference, October 18-20, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- RTC Meeting, December 3, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- State Educational Theatre Association memos, notes, newsletters, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- State Educational Theatre Association Governing documents, memos, correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- ANTA Theatre Playbills, Regional Theatre Council, American National Theatre and Academy, 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 3)
- American Community Theatre Association conference programs and "encore" newsletters, Dallas theatre brochure, 1960-1961, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Theatre Programs (1 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Theatre Programs (2 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Theatre Programs (3 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Theatre Programs (4 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Theatre Programs (5 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Theatre Programs (6 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Theatre Programs (7 of 7), 1938-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)